import {UnderlineText, SquareRoot, superscript, subscript, BoldText, ItalicText, Fraction, ShortFraction, LongFraction, MixedFraction, Isotopes } from "@/mathnotation"

export const ENGLISHLANGUAGEA2015 = [

{
instruction: "In each of the following sentences, there is a word underlined, and one gap. From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the word that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the underlined word and that will, at the same time, correctly fill the gap in the sentence.",
id: "question1",
question: ["1. While Araba showed great ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"aptitude"}/>, " in the test, her sister was quite _________________"],
A: "nervous.",
B: "dissatisfied.",
C: "incapable.",
D: "afraid.",
answer: "A. nervous",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: ["2. The students registered their ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"disapproval"}/>, " when the self-satisfied SRC thought they would _________________ their efforts."],
A: "accept",
B: "appreciate",
C: "remember",
D: "proclaim",
answer: "B. appreciate",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: ["3. Rather than ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"pacify"}/>, " the woman, the gift _________________ her."],
A: "disturbed",
B: "infuriated",
C: "offended",
D: "tormented",
answer: "B. infuriated",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: ["4. What made you think I was the ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"master"}/>, " and he the _________________ ?"],
A: "apprentice",
B: "maid",
C: "recruit",
D: "amateur",
answer: "A. apprentice",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: ["5. he thicket was rather ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"dense,"}/>, " not the _________________  growth we expected from the description we had been given."],
A: "sparse",
B: "arid",
C: "bare",
D: "wild",
answer: "A. sparse",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: ["6. Kafui’s ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"fame"}/>, " as a philanthropist soared as high as his brother’s _________________ as a swindler."],
A: "unfamiliarity",
B: "notoriety",
C: "disgrace",
D: "disrespect",
answer: "B. notoriety",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: ["7. The litigant was ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"smart"}/>, " so he took the land from his _________________ friend."],
A: "timid",
B: "slow",
C: "scared",
D: "dull",
answer: "D. dull",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: ["8. The investigators reported that they had searched the ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"entire"}/>, " compound when they had only searched the area _________________ "],
A: "in its.",
B: "carelessly.",
C: "unevenly.",
D: "partially.",
answer: "D. partially",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: ["9. Seconds later, Aku ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"emerged"}/>, " from under the tarpaulin where Akweley had just _________________ "],
A: "returned.",
B: "visited.",
C: "set off.",
D: "disappeared.",
answer: "D. disappeared",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: ["10. If you ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"hide"}/>, " the criminal, you will be prosecuted, but if you _________________ him, you may get a reward."],
A: "uncover",
B: "expose",
C: "reveal",
D: "betray",
answer: "C. reveal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
section: "II",
instruction: "From the list of words lettered A to D, choose the one that best completes each of the following sentences.",
id: "question11",
question: "11. The boys stole the mangoes, _________________ ",
A: "do they?",
B: "didn’t they?",
C: "were they?",
D: "weren’t they?",
answer: "B. didn’t they?",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. I was advised _________________ talking in class.",
A: "against",
B: "on",
C: "for",
D: "with",
answer: "A. against",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. All of us saw the man _________________ up the bucket.",
A: "pick",
B: "picked",
C: "to pick",
D: "to have picked",
answer: "A. pick",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Ayariga, with five friends, _________________ arriving today.",
A: "is",
B: "were",
C: "are",
D: "to be",
answer: "A. is",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. The man arrived _________________ car.",
A: "with",
B: "for",
C: "by",
D: "within",
answer: "C. by",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. When I was in London, _________________ ",
A: "I put up with Jojo.",
B: "Jojo put up by me",
C: "I was put up by Jojo.",
D: "Jojo and I put up.",
answer: "C. I was put up by Jojo",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. Ten men sat _________________ on the case.",
A: "by",
B: "on",
C: "in",
D: "up",
answer: "B. on",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. It never rains, but it _________________ ",
A: "is pouring.",
B: "poured.",
C: "wil pour",
D: "pours.",
answer: "D. pours",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. I am speaking on behalf _________________ my friend.",
A: "of",
B: "for",
C: "with",
D: "by",
answer: "A. of",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. Musa took _________________ me the first day we met.",
A: "after",
B: "in",
C: "to",
D: "with",
answer: "C. to",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
section: "III",
instruction: "Choose from the alternatives lettered A to D the one which is nearest in meaning to the underlined word or expression in each sentence.",
id: "question21",
question: ["21. The visitors were ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"prevailed"}/>, " upon to spend another night."],
A: "allowed",
B: "persuaded",
C: "encouraged",
D: "begged",
answer: "B. persuaded",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: ["22. Do not make ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"derogatory"}/>, " remarks; they spoil mutual goodwill."],
A: "crude",
B: "harsh",
C: "negative",
D: "cruel",
answer: "C. negative",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: ["23. All these problems were ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"brought"}/>, " about by your carelessness."],
A: "originated",
B: "complicated",
C: "caused",
D: "supported",
answer: "C. caused",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: ["24. The school rules are rather ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"lax."}/>, ""],
A: "powerless",
B: "weak",
C: "flexible",
D: "harmless",
answer: "C. flexible",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: ["25. Joseph is the most disciplined football ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"enthusiast"}/>, " I know."],
A: "patron",
B: "defender",
C: "fan",
D: "sympathiser",
answer: "C. fan",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: ["26. It is the ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"pressure"}/>, " of work that has necessitated his early retirement."],
A: "strain",
B: "weight",
C: "volume",
D: "bitterness",
answer: "A. strain",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: ["27. After the match it was obvious that the refree was ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"biased."}/>, ""],
A: "generous",
B: "lenient",
C: "partial",
D: "favourable",
answer: "C. partial",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: ["28. How else could we ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"have"}/>, " gone through the spate of harassment?"],
A: "suffered",
B: "endured",
C: "sustained",
D: "escaped",
answer: "A. suffered",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: ["29. Seventeen people ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"indicated"}/>, " by their attendance that they will not resign."],
A: "declared",
B: "intended",
C: "showed",
D: "notified",
answer: "C. showed",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: ["30. That had been my ", <UnderlineText key={"1"} text={"fervent"}/>, " desire."],
A: "forceful",
B: "ardent",
C: "biggest",
D: "precious",
answer: "B. ardent",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
section: "IV",
id: "question31",
instruction: "After each of the following sentences, a list of possible interpretations of all or part of the sentence is given. Choose the interpretation you consider most appropriate for each sentence.",
question: "31. If you are not careful, by the time we are through with this, you will be laughing on the wrong side of your face. This means that you will soon",
A: "fall into a coma.",
B: "be in trouble.",
C: "go home early.",
D: "start smiling broadly.",
answer: "B. be in trouble",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. Before the game, Akologo’s team had been considered the underdogs. This means that the team had",
A: "lost most of its supporters.",
B: "lost the previous match.",
C: "not been rated highly.",
D: "been rated the favourite to win.",
answer: "C. not been rated highly",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. That was a hard nut to crack. This means that it was a",
A: "difficult problem to solve.",
B: "problem that caused confusion.",
C: "problem we had never faced before.",
D: "purely business problem.",
answer: "A. difficult problem to solve",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. When you agreed to host the crooks, you signed your death warrant. This means that you",
A: "placed yourself in imminent danger.",
B: "saved your own life narrowly.",
C: "signed your will.",
D: "punished yourself unnecessarily.",
answer: "A. placed yourself in imminent danger",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. If that is the man’s version, we must take it with a pinch of salt. This means that we must",
A: "eat our food with some salt.",
B: "not believe it completely.",
C: "trust the man’s judgement in future.",
D: "ignore whatever the man says.",
answer: "B. not believe it completely",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. He had a close shave with death. This means that he",
A: "died immediately.",
B: "died later.",
C: "almost died.",
D: "lost a lot of blood.",
answer: "C. almost died",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. Justina is the apple of her father’s eye. This means that Justina",
A: "causes a lot of trouble for her father.",
B: "is her father’s favourite daughter.",
C: "may be the worst girl in the family.",
D: "provides apples for her father.",
answer: "B. is her father’s favourite daughter",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. If you mean it is Ajaara, you are barking up the wrong tree. This means that",
A: "you have guessed right.",
B: "your dog has misled you.",
C: "your suspicion is wrong.",
D: "you are giving Ajaara the wrong name.",
answer: "C. your suspicion is wrong",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. It is no use sweeping these issues under the carpet. This means that",
A: "you cannot speak the truth.",
B: "you cannot conceal the truth.",
C: "sweeping under the carpet is unnecessary.",
D: "your attempt to cover these issues will succeed.",
answer: "B. you cannot conceal the truth",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. From his behaviour, you could guess that he had a skeleton in the cupboard. This means that he had",
A: "a frightening behaviour.",
B: "hidden a skeleton in his cupboard.",
C: "an unpleasant secret to hide",
D: "a lot to say.",
answer: "C. an unpleasant secret to hide",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
section: "V",
passage: "In the following passage, the numbered gaps indicate missing words. Against each number in the list below the passage, four choices are offered in columns lettered A to D. For each numbered gap, choose from the options provided for that number, the word that is most suitable to fill the gap. Two days after the – 41- our team returned. They had stayed on to – 42- the rest of the – 43 – after being – 44 – out by The Lions. They had, in the – 45 – match, – 46 – five goals against two by The Leopards. But they were later – 47- by The Tigers before meeting The Lions. The Lions out played our team. Their ball – 48 – was 65%, and they committed very few – 49 – . Our team, however, even earned a red card and had to finish playing the match with ten men when they were one goal -50-.",
id: "question41",
question: "41. *********************",
A: "tournament",
B: "game",
C: "encounter",
D: "contest",
answer: "A. Tournament",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. *********************",
A: "observe",
B: "watch",
C: "view",
D: "see",
answer: "B. Watch",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. *********************",
A: "sports",
B: "bouts",
C: "series",
D: "matches",
answer: "D. Matches",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. *********************",
A: "kicked",
B: "pushed",
C: "thrown",
D: "knocked",
answer: "A. Kicked",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. *********************",
A: "opening",
B: "initial",
C: "first",
D: "beginning",
answer: "A. Opening",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. *********************",
A: "scored",
B: "earned",
C: "secured",
D: "gained",
answer: "A. Scored",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. *********************",
A: "suppress",
B: "overpowered",
C: "conquered",
D: "beaten",
answer: "D. Beaten",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. *********************",
A: "protection",
B: "possession",
C: "handling",
D: "dribbling",
answer: "B. Dribbling",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. *********************",
A: "mistakes",
B: "faults",
C: "fouls",
D: "penalties",
answer: "C. Fouls",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. *********************",
A: "away",
B: "down",
C: "beaten",
D: "out",
answer: "B. Down",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
section: "I",
instruction: "Charles Dickens: Oliver Twist \nRead the following extract and answer Questions 51 to 53. \n“You’ve raised a artificial soul and spirit in him, ma’am unbecoming a person of his condition: as the board, Mr Sowerberry, who are practical philosophers, will tell you. What have paupers to do with soul or spirit? It’s quite enough that we let ’em live bodies”",
id: "question51",
question: "51. What is the figure of speech of the underlined expression?",
A: "Assonance",
B: "Alliteration",
C: "Rhetorical question",
D: "Satirical question",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question52",
question: "52. Where was this speech made?",
A: "At the workhouse.",
B: "At Fagin’s place.",
C: "At Sowerberry’s workshop.",
D: "At Bumble’s home..",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question53",
question: "53. What incident had occasioned this speech?",
A: "Noah Claypole’s relationship with Charlotte.",
B: "Oliver’s rebellion.",
C: "Mrs Sowerberry’s kindness.",
D: "Mr Bumble’s concern for Oliver.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: ["Read the following extract and answer Questions 54 to 56. \n“As he drew nearer to this house, a feeling came over him that he had seen it before That garden wall! On the grass inside, he had fallen on his knees last night, and prayed the two men’s mercy.”"],
id: "question54",
question: "54. What was “this house”?",
A: "The house at the market.",
B: "The house where Oliver was kidnapped.",
C: "The house where Monks met Mr Bumble.",
D: "The house they had attempted to rob.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question55",
question: "55. two men’s refers to",
A: "Fagin and Artful Dodger.",
B: "Sikes and Monks.",
C: "Toby Crackit and Sikes.",
D: "Giless and Brittles.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question56",
question: "56. What reason did Oliver have for going to the house?",
A: "It was better to die near human beings.",
B: "To give himself up as the thief.",
C: "He hoped to find his friends there.",
D: "To seek refuge from his enemies.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Read the following extract and answer Questions 57 to 60. \n“The girl had taken a few restless turns to and fro closely watched meanwhile by her hidden observer when the heavy bell of St. Paul’s tolled for the death of another day. The chambers of birth and death, of health and sickness, the rigid face of the corpse and calm sleep of the child”",
id: "question57",
question: "57. Who was her hidden observer?",
A: "Oliver Twist",
B: "Charley Bates",
C: "The Artful Dodger",
D: "Noah Claypole",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question58",
question: "58. How was the girl able to get away from home to keep the appointment?",
A: "By drugging her lover.",
B: "By pleading on her knees.",
C: "By tricking her lover.",
D: "By bribing the watchman.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question59",
question: "59. What is the figure of speech used in the underlined expression?",
A: "Metaphor",
B: "Oxymoron",
C: "Personification",
D: "Exaggeration",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question60",
question: "60. What is dominant mood in the extract?",
A: "Hope",
B: "Hatred",
C: "Fear",
D: "Bliss",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
section: "II",
instruction: "Lawrence Darmani: Grief Child \nRead the following extract and answer Questions 51 to 53. \n“That was as far as Nimo went. Casually. He hadn’t expected Nimo so confidently, to confide in him or to ask him to pray for his son. When Nimo came to him yesterday and said he had something to discuss, he thought the man only needed help _________________ ..”",
id: "question51",
question: "51. What kind of help did Yaro think Nimo needed?",
A: "Wood work",
B: "Herbal preparation",
C: "Farm work",
D: "Hut repairs",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question52",
question: "52. Why did Nimo ask for special prayers for his son?",
A: "He wanted spiritual protection for his son.",
B: "For peace to prevail.",
C: "His son had a bad dream",
D: "For academic brilliance",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question53",
question: "53. What was the most admirable feature of Yaro’s character?",
A: "Friendliness",
B: "Patience",
C: "Diligence",
D: "Discipline",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question54",
question: "54. Why did Goma go to Nimo at Suza?",
A: "For consultation on herbal practice.",
B: "For land request.",
C: "For permission to travel.",
D: "For financial assistance.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Read the following extract and answer quetsions 55 to 57. \n“This one is good? Nimo said and dropped the root into the khaki bag hanging on the boy’s shoulder. The sun had set beyond the trees and the invisible crickets had begun their night calls.”",
id: "question55",
question: "55. What figure of speech has been used in the underlined expression?",
A: "Euphemism",
B: "Alliteration",
C: "Personification",
D: "Exaggeration",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question56",
question: "56. What are the two characters doing?",
A: "Collecting herbs",
B: "Hunting for snails",
C: "Setting landmarks",
D: "Engaging farm hands",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question57",
question: "57. Whom had Nimo first treated for dislocation?",
A: "Appiah’s wife",
B: "Anane",
C: "Teacher Ofori",
D: "Siaka",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Read the following extract and answer Questions 58 to 60. \n“Beckie turned. Ofori had been smiling, but Beckie looked serious. For a brief moment the two lovers looked into each others’ eyes.”",
id: "question58",
question: "58. What was Beckie’s mood?",
A: "Indignation",
B: "Rejection",
C: "She was hesitant.",
D: "She was unruffled.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question59",
question: "59. Where had Teacher Ofori been?",
A: "In Suza.",
B: "In Abenase.",
C: "With the linguist.",
D: "With the headteacher.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question60",
question: "60. What did Ofori tell Beckie later?",
A: "To be his study mate.",
B: "To be his friend.",
C: "To be his wife.",
D: "To be his work mate.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Drama \nAnswer any set of 10 questions numbered 61 to 70 in either Section I or Section II.",
section: "I",
passage: "W. Shakespeare: Much Ado About Nothing. \nRead the following extract and answer quetsions 61 to 64. \nBeatrice:  _________________ . He wears his faith but as the fashion of his hat; it ever changes with the next block. Messenger: I see, \nLady, the gentleman is not in your books.",
id: "question61",
question: "61. “He” refers to",
A: "Leonato.",
B: "Benedick.",
C: "Antonio.",
D: "Claudio.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question62",
question: "62. “The gentleman is not in your books” means Beatrice",
A: "is not aware of the gentleman’s sterling qualities.",
B: "has not recorded the gentleman’s name in the list of visitors.",
C: "does not like the gentleman.",
D: "does not know the gentleman.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question63",
question: "63. What is the setting of the dialogue?",
A: "Leonato’s house",
B: "Antonio’s house",
C: "The garden",
D: "The chapel",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question64",
question: "64. Where are the visitors they are expecting coming from?",
A: "From celebrating a festival.",
B: "From the king’s coronation.",
C: "From a treasure hunt.",
D: "From fighting a war.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Read the following extract and answer Questions 65 to 68. \nMargaret: I like the new tire within excellently, if the hair were a thought browner; and your gown’s _________________ a most rare fashion, faith \nHero: O that exceeds, the say",
id: "question65",
question: "65. Margaret compares Hero’s gown to that of the",
A: "Duchess of Milan.",
B: "Queen of Aragon.",
C: "Duchess of Padua.",
D: "Queen of Florence.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question66",
question: "66. What has occasioned this outburst?",
A: "Hero’s plan to match Beatrice and Benedict.",
B: "Margaret’s relationship with Comrade",
C: "The watch people’s activities.",
D: "Hero’s wedding ceremony.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question67",
question: "67. What is the mood of Hero on this occasion?",
A: "Ecstatic",
B: "Sorrowful",
C: "Hesitant",
D: "Expectant",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question68",
question: "68. Who comes there soon after?",
A: "Claudio and his friends",
B: "Don John and his accomplices",
C: "Leonato and Antonio",
D: "The two watch officers",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Read the following extract and answer Questions 69 to 70. \nDon Pedro: How now! two of my brother’s men bound ...... \nClaudio: Hearken after their offence, my lord. \nDon Pedro: Officers, what offence have these men done?",
id: "question69",
question: "69. What is the offence?",
A: "Refusing to go to war",
B: "Slandering plot against Hero",
C: "Treason plot against the governor",
D: "Eloping with the ladies",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question70",
question: "70. How does Leonato react to Claudio wronging Hero?",
A: "He asks for Friar’s intervention.",
B: "He sues Claudio at the Palace court.",
C: "He challenges Claudio to a duel.",
D: "He demands monetary compensation.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
section: "II",
instruction: "Efo Kojo Mawugbe: In the Chest of a Woman. \nRead the following extract and answer Questions 61 to 65. \nOkyeame Bonsu: Your Highness, a delegation of three has arrived in the palace with a message. Nana Yaa: And what is the message?",
id: "question61",
question: "61. What had Nana Yaa and Owusu been doing shortly before the arrival of the delegation?",
A: "They had been working on the farm.",
B: "They had been playing oware.",
C: "They had been weaving cloth.",
D: "They had been telling stories.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question62",
question: "62. Who is the leader of the delegation?",
A: "Nana Oppong",
B: "Kwesi Amoako",
C: "Okyeame Boateng",
D: "Okyeame Bonsu",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question63",
question: "63. How did Nana Yaa ascertain that the delegation came from the right source?",
A: "She examined the symbol of office.",
B: "She examined their haircut.",
C: "She examined their amulets",
D: "She examined the patterns on their clothes.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question64",
question: "64. What did the examination reveal?",
A: "The delegation was to understudy the custodians.",
B: "The delegation was to undergo training course in kingship.",
C: "The delegation was to make marriage arrangements.",
D: "The delegation was on a peace mission.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question65",
question: "65. “And what is the message?” The message is to",
A: "send the heir apparent to Nkwanta..",
B: "demand royalties for stool lands.",
C: "settle disputes.",
D: "choose the next king.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question66",
question: "66. What system of inheritance was practised there?",
A: "Patrilineal system",
B: "Ancestral system",
C: "Divine system",
D: "Matrilineal system",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question67",
question: "67. Walls have ears. What figure of speech has been used in the expression?",
A: "Paradox",
B: "Personification",
C: "Hyperbole",
D: "Oxymoron",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Read the following extract and answer Questions 68 to 70. \nKING: It is so. my nephew \nYou ought to rest your buttocks on the judgement stool. At least three times, before whatever pronouncement you make shall be binding. It is the custom.",
id: "question68",
question: "68. How was this declaration received by the audience?",
A: "With approval",
B: "With indifference",
C: "With disdain",
D: "With suspicion",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question69",
question: "69. What was the mood of the addressee?",
A: "Felt ashamed",
B: "Felt sad",
C: "Felt threatened",
D: "Felt angry",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question70",
question: "70. How was the addressee’s vows sealed?",
A: "With dancing",
B: "With clapping",
C: "With horn blowing",
D: "With gong-gong beating",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Poetry \nAnswer any set of 10 questions numbered 71 to 80 in either Section I or Section II. \nNon-African Poetry \nRobert Frost: Stopping by Woods on a Snowy Evening.",
section: "I",
id: "question71",
question: "71. Line 1 — “Whose woods these are I think I know” is an example of",
A: "irony.",
B: "simile.",
C: "inversion.",
D: "allusion.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question72",
question: "72. What is the setting of the poem?",
A: "In the morning",
B: "In the evening",
C: "At noon",
D: "At midnight George Herbert: Death.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question73",
question: "73. The theme of the poem is",
A: "death makes all people equal.",
B: "loss of life and senses.",
C: "flesh and bones.",
D: "death is no longer frightening.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question74",
question: "74. “Death, thou wast once an uncouth hideous thing” is an example of",
A: "apostrohpe.",
B: "litotes.",
C: "metonymy.",
D: "metaphor.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "William Blake: The Tiger.",
id: "question75",
question: "75. The dominant literary device in the poem is",
A: "satirical question.",
B: "rhetorical question.",
C: "interrogative sentence.",
D: "metaphorical statement.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question76",
question: "76. The beauty of the poem lies in the",
A: "appropriate use of diction.",
B: "superb contrast between two unique animals.",
C: "arrangement of the stanzas.",
D: "deep insight into the supernatural.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "George Herbert: Death. G. C. Lord Byron: She Walks in Beauty.",
id: "question77",
question: "77. “ _________________ . cloudless climes and stormy skies” is an example of",
A: "flashback.",
B: "assonance.",
C: "alliteration.",
D: "metaphor.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question78",
question: "78. What is the mood of the poem?",
A: "Devoted reverence",
B: "Affectionate joy",
C: "Passionate appeal",
D: "Mixed feeling Mohan Singh: A Village Girl.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question79",
question: "79. “Tall and slim like a sugar cane” is an example of",
A: "sarcasm.",
B: "hyperbole.",
C: "simile.",
D: "symbolism.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question80",
question: "80. “Mustard flowers peep through the green grass” is an example of",
A: "exaggeration.",
B: "apostrophe.",
C: "parallelism.",
D: "personification.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
section: "II",
instruction: "African Poetry J.P. Clark: Night Rain.",
id: "question71",
question: "71. The theme of the poem is",
A: "strategic positions in the house.",
B: "rainy season.",
C: "hope in the midst of poverty.",
D: "rural poverty.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question72",
question: "72. “But turn, brother, turn upon your side.” The repetition of turn in the line above evokes",
A: "worry and anxiety.",
B: "hope and encouragement.",
C: "caution and obedience.",
D: "happiness and contentment.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Kojo Gyinae Kyei: I Have Been a Victim.",
id: "question73",
question: "73. “This robot called tribe.” By comparing tribe to robot the persona considers tribe as",
A: "thoughtful and secure.",
B: "careless and individualistic.",
C: "indifferent and uncertain.",
D: "unfeeling and insensitive.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question74",
question: "74. ”When once my father departed” is an example of",
A: "euphemism.",
B: "litotes.",
C: "metonym.",
D: "metaphor.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Kwabena Eyi Acquah: Gently.",
id: "question75",
question: "75. “For better days that never came.” The line above evokes feelings of",
A: "loneliness.",
B: "disturbance.",
C: "hopelessness.",
D: "annoyance.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question76",
question: "76. “To them this was home” is an example of",
A: "sarcasm.",
B: "flashback.",
C: "allusion.",
D: "inversion.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
instruction: "Richard Ntiru: The Pauper.",
id: "question77",
question: "77. ”You simply lean on a leafless tree” is an example of",
A: "sarcasm.",
B: "symbolism.",
C: "alliteration.",
D: "assonance.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question78",
question: "78. ”Your ribs and bones reflecting the light?” What does the line above say about the pauper’s condition?",
A: "Dream-like state",
B: "Abject poverty",
C: "Developed stature",
D: "Joyful circumstances Jared Angira: No Coffin, No Grave.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question79",
question: "79. The line “And let lice lick our intestines” evokes feelings of",
A: "condemnation.",
B: "repugnance.",
C: "satisfaction.",
D: "fear.",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question80",
question: "80. “The scavengers performed the post-mortem.” What literary device has been used in the line above?",
A: "Personification",
B: "Metaphor",
C: "Apostrophe",
D: "Paradox",
answer: "A. zzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},



]